import { QuestionType, SubjectCode } from "./utils";

const subject_code = SubjectCode.LINGUISTICS;
export const Linguistics: QuestionType[] = [
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the study of the structure and formation of words known as?",
    option_a: "Syntax",
    option_b: "Morphology",
    option_c: "Phonetics",
    option_d: "Semantics",
    correct_option: "Morphology",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which of the following is a branch of linguistics that deals with the sounds of speech?",
    option_a: "Syntax",
    option_b: "Phonetics",
    option_c: "Morphology",
    option_d: "Pragmatics",
    correct_option: "Phonetics",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "In linguistics, what term is used to describe the study of meaning in language?",
    option_a: "Phonology",
    option_b: "Syntax",
    option_c: "Semantics",
    option_d: "Pragmatics",
    correct_option: "Semantics",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for a system of communication using gestures, facial expressions, and body movements instead of speech?",
    option_a: "Pidgin",
    option_b: "Sign Language",
    option_c: "Creole",
    option_d: "Jargon",
    correct_option: "Sign Language",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which linguistic theory proposes that language shapes and limits the way people think?",
    option_a: "Sapir-Whorf hypothesis",
    option_b: "Chomskyan theory",
    option_c: "Structuralism",
    option_d: "Generative grammar",
    correct_option: "Sapir-Whorf hypothesis",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "In linguistics, what is the term for a word that has the opposite meaning of another word?",
    option_a: "Synonym",
    option_b: "Homonym",
    option_c: "Antonym",
    option_d: "Homophone",
    correct_option: "Antonym",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the study of how languages change and develop over time called?",
    option_a: "Etymology",
    option_b: "Dialectology",
    option_c: "Historical Linguistics",
    option_d: "Sociolinguistics",
    correct_option: "Historical Linguistics",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which linguistic subfield focuses on the social aspects of language, including variations in speech and dialects?",
    option_a: "Sociolinguistics",
    option_b: "Neurolinguistics",
    option_c: "Psycholinguistics",
    option_d: "Anthropological Linguistics",
    correct_option: "Sociolinguistics",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What term refers to the smallest unit of sound that can change the meaning of a word?",
    option_a: "Phoneme",
    option_b: "Morpheme",
    option_c: "Syllable",
    option_d: "Grapheme",
    correct_option: "Phoneme",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which linguistic concept describes the rules governing the structure of sentences in a language?",
    option_a: "Morphology",
    option_b: "Phonology",
    option_c: "Syntax",
    option_d: "Pragmatics",
    correct_option: "Syntax",
    subject_code,
  },
];
